Contact

+34 618380017 (Mobile) luis@palaciorestrepo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/Impalacio (LinkedIn) www.palaciorestrepo.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Virtual Reality (VR)
Augmented Reality (AR)
Unity

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Máster en Programación de Videojuegos con Unity® 2020 y C# CS50's Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with Python

Luis M. Palacio

MSc in Cognitive Systems and Interactive Media | AR | VR | XR | Unity | Game Development

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Summary

Passionate about technologies that evoke emotions and create momentous. Which has driven my career towards AR/VR development specializing in XR Interactions and Immersive Experiences.

I have been in the industry since 2016, and I dream in a world where anyone could reach their full potential with immersive technologies. Moreover, with a background in entertainment and cognitive systems, I am very interested in Social Computing and the cultural implications of Artificial Intelligence.

Videogames help me advance my soft-skills, specially empathy and competitiveness. They guide me to become a better team player capable to lead my partners to success.

Experience

studioborabora Creative Technologist January 2023 - Present (1 year 11 months) Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Unity AR/VR and WebGL development

DTOWN

Chief Technology Officer August 2020 - December 2022 (2 years 5 months) Valencia, Valencian Community, Spain

- Exploration of cutting-edge technology related to Extended Reality by using Fast-prototyping techniques to develop experimental applications for Hololens, NReal AR Glasses, Mobile-based AR, and Virtual Reality devices; including interactive 360 videos, Motion Capture, LiDar scans, and Photogrammetry.
- Participant and speaker in VRDays 2021 Europe.

- PR/Merged +4000 commits to develop working MVP with Multiplayer System, Virtual spaces, Interactive elements, and In-game creation tools.
- Whitepaper definition based on deep market research focused on the Metaverse Industry.
- Lead Developer of a small team intended to build a whitelabel Metaverse compatible with AR, VR, and Desktop devices.
- Definition of main features, architecture, and Customer Journey Map for an experimental virtual world inspired by the 90's Sci-fi movies.

TODO1 Services Inc.

1 year 7 months

Innovation Developer August 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Antioquia Area, Colombia

- Conceptualize and Design prototypes; test and deploy key features including API networking, NLP for virtual assistants/chatbots, and development of mobile applications.
- Formulate and implement new design decisions and product directions based on user testing observations.
- Leverage user testing observations to create and implement innovative product directions and design decisions.
- Employ critical thinking and complex problem-solving skills to identify potential areas for improvement and create actionable solutions.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams toward the timely achievement of project and organizational objectives under Scrum-based methodologies.

Apprentice of Innovation February 2018 - August 2018 (7 months)

Antioquia Area, Colombia

- Design and development of applications focused on the financial sector.
- Implementation and deployment of virtual assistants/chatbots on Facebook Messenger and Skype For Business.
- Development of mobile applications in Android, iOS, and Web Mobile; using OutSystems and Unity C#.
- Participation in projects from their early stages of conceptualization until its MVP is reached.

Wizard Fun Factory S.A.S System Software Developer September 2017 - September 2017 (1 month)

Envigado, Antioquia, Colombia

• Definition and implementation of low-level protocols to communicate interactive installations, including lights control, sensors, and Unity applications.

Education

Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Master in Cognitive Systems and Interactive Media, Human Computer Interaction · (September 2019 - August 2020)

Universitat Politècnica de València (UPV)

Master in Visual Arts and Multimedia · (September 2021 - September 2024)

Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana

Digital Entertainment Engineering, Engineering (2014 - 2018)